Today we're talking about content
systems. If you want to learn how to
make great content faster without
sacrificing originality, this is going
to be one of the best workflows you ever
learn. Now, I know this works because
this is the exact same system I'm
personally running every single day. I
have a million followers. I've done
billions of views. And this month alone,
I'll post over 50 unique short form
videos on Instagram alone. And these
aren't clips or AI slop. These are
native premium short form videos that'll
get tens of millions of views and drive
thousands of leads. The only way that
much premium volume is possible is by
building this type of content system.
Now, I'll be honest, the truth is, as
weird as it sounds, I've never really
liked making content. And the reason why
is because there's just so much
repetitive work that goes into every
single rep. It's just draining to do
every day. And so, what I needed was a
system that allowed me to use AI to
automate the boring parts so that I
could free up more of my time to be
creative on the fun parts. And that's
exactly what I built. So, in this video,
I'm going to take you through my entire
AI powered content system. First, we'll
go through one rep end to end across my
six-step workflow, and then at the end
of the video, I'll take you through my
10X badge system for how you grow as
fast as possible on any platform. Now,
the first part I want to focus on is my
endto-end workflow. And I think this
will be the most valuable 10 to 15
minutes you watch on content for the
rest of this year. To make one video, I
go through the same six stages every
single time. topic, format, substance,
hook, script, and edit. Now, in every
one of those stages, I'm able to use AI
to speed up the process without
sacrificing creativity or originality.
So, here's how the process works in
detail. Step one is always topic. The
very first thing I do is figure out what
topic I'm going to make the video about,
cuz the truth is nothing else really
matters if you pick a losing topic. Now,
for topic, this first step, I lean
completely on data and AI. My creativity
in this workflow comes a little bit
later in substance, hook, and scripting
and sometimes the edit, but I don't need
to reinvent the wheel on the topic
front. You can just use data to get the
best topics. And the reason why is
because of the psychology of the viewer
and buyer. In every niche, there are
certain topics that always outperform
others, and those map to whatever the
categories or topics that those viewers
think are more important. Now, to use
data and build a workflow for solving
topics, I use Sandcastles.ai plus
Claude. That's the money combo and it
crushes everything else. The first thing
I do is I go to Sandcastles and I build
a watch list of all the top performing
channels in my niche. Now, you may
already know who these people are, but
even if you don't, you can just click
describe and write in the type of
content you make and Sand Castles will
suggest all the best performing channels
for you to track. I like to get anywhere
from 20 to 30 channels in my watch list
before I move to the next step. Now, for
me, the sweet spot when I'm adding those
channels is the micro, small, and medium
account size range between 10,000
followers and a million. You don't want
to go any bigger than that. By the way,
the reason I'm building out this channel
list instead of just scrolling
mindlessly is because I'm trying to
speed this up. I don't want any noise.
When you scroll, you get so much noise.
Sometimes you find good videos, but a
lot of noise. This reduces all the
noise, so it's only signal. Okay, once I
have that channel list made, there's two
more things I'm going to do in Sand
Castles before I go to Claude. The first
thing is I'm going to go to the videos
tab. I'm going to go sort and I'm going
to sort by outlier score. Then I'm going
to set the posted date to either three
or six months depending on how far you
want to look back. And I'm going to set
the minimum bound on engagement rate to
2%. This will give you the best videos
from that channel set in the relative
range you want to analyze. Now, this may
reveal only 15 videos. It might reveal
500 videos. It depends on how many
channels you have in your list and how
many bangers those channels have made.
The next step is to deep analyze every
single one of these videos. And you can
do it by hovering over any of them and
pressing analyze. Or you can bulk
analyze by pressing the bulk button and
then specifying the number of videos you
want to do. Personally, I like doing a
hundred at a time. You can do less than
100, but the more you do, the better
those trends will be when you're
analyzing it in aggregate. So, the more
the better. Now, when you deep analyze
and you click in, you'll realize you get
everything you'd ever want on the video.
The transcript information about the
topic, the idea, the hook format, the
exact hook, the storytelling format,
literally everything. And the best part
of Sandcastle is now you can export all
that information across all the top 100
videos out into a CSV. And we're going
to upload that CSV into Claude in a
minute. Now, before we go to Claude,
there's one other thing I like to do in
Sand Castles to set myself up for the
next round of doing this in the future.
I go to the automations tab and I write
an automation rule. All I do is put five
in the outlier score and then 2% in
engagement. So, what that means is
anytime any of my channels on my watch
list post a video above a 5x outlier in
the future, this automation will
automatically process it for me. So,
when I come back into Sandcastles, it's
just ready to go and I don't need to go
through that bulk analysis process. It
just basically autodetects outliers for
you. So, I like to set that and then
move forward. All right, back to the
main flow. I've got my CSV of the top
100 videos. I'm going to open Claude and
I'm going to drag that CSV into Claude.
And when I use Claude, I use the desktop
app and I'm using Co-work. You can use
chat, co-work, or claude code. In the
browser, which is what most people do,
they just type in claude.ai. They can
only use chat. So co-work is way more
powerful. You should be using co-work or
claude code for this. Now, I'm going to
go through the exact prompt that I feed
into Claude to do this topic research
right now. But by the way, all these
prompts I mentioned in this video,
there'll be like four or five prompts
throughout, I've got a doc below. It's
completely free where I've written down
all those prompts. You can just copy
paste. So you don't have to worry about
like scrambling and copying what I'm
saying word for word. But I'm going to
say it word for word on this first one
so that you can get a sense of what
we're doing. All right. So this is the
prompt that I'm going to run in Claude
right away when I first get the CSV in.
I'm uploading a report of the top 100
videos in my niche over the last X
months. Whatever you put in for post
date, 3 months, 6 months, whatever it
is. These were posted by the top
creators in my niche. Now, if you
haven't set up the background, you're
going to use this background part as
well. For background, I make content in
Xnich. For me, it's like social media
marketing, social media growth with the
goal of helping build an audience of Y
avatar. For me, it's business owners
that are trying to grow on social media.
Specifically, my target authority
statement is I help X people with Y
thing to accomplish Z goal or to get Z
outcome. So, for me, it's I help
business owners grow faster on social
media so they can build their business.
First, I want you to go through the list
and screen out any videos that aren't on
the topic that I'd be covering. So, if
there's any random trend or personal
story from the creator that isn't on
topic, get rid of those. With the videos
you have left, run two analyses for me.
First, I want you to list all the videos
in order by outlier score. I want you to
give me the topic, the link to the
original video, and a one to twoline
sentence pitching me on why you think
this would be a good video to make given
my target authority statement. The topic
should not be at the category level.
They should be a three to five word
framing that summarizes what the video
is about specifically. Some of these may
overlap, but I'd expect dozens and
dozens of unique topics. Now, second, I
want you to run another analysis
clustering the videos by topic category.
There's no specific set number of topic
buckets I'm going for, but I want clear
delineation and break points between.
I'd expect somewhere between 8 to 15
different categories. I want you to rank
these buckets in order based on highest
average outlier score from the videos
within them. Within each bucket, I also
want you to list the individual videos.
I want you to give me the topic. I want
you to give me the link to the original
and then again the one to tweline
sentence explaining why this would be a
good video for me to make. Now, once you
have that, just run it. It will take
about 4 to 5 minutes to finish. And when
it finishes, this will give you the best
datadriven list of topics for your niche
without any scrolling required. Now, my
process is if I don't have an original
idea I want to make, I'm always starting
with this list. And it doesn't mean I
make every single one of those, but I
start with the top one and I ask myself
when I get to the substance, do I have
something unique to say? If I don't, I
pass. But I have the right to make any
of them if I want. This is how you use
data to get a curated list of topics
that you already know worked. And the
reason this looks so easy is because of
that Sandcastle's data. Having the
transcript and all that detailed
information about every video, you'll
see how powerful it gets with that one
report. We can basically run this full
flow. And if you're a social media
manager or you do this for many clients,
you just save yourself literally dozens
of hours a week because of how many
times you have to do this. Okay, so
that's step one, validated topic curated
by data. Now, step two in the flow is
the format. And this step is extremely
quick, but I will not move to step
three, the substance, until I've decided
what format I'm making. Now, the format
is usually a combination of the
structure of the video, the way the
points are laid out, and sometimes the
visual execution of how it's edited. All
three of those things together kind of
combine to make the format. So, for
example, a breakdown format is actually
very flexible. It doesn't lock you into
a certain narrative or story type. But
an S tier format, on the other hand, one
where you're like ranking items across
the S, a B, C, D, F tier, that kind of
dictates how you have to flow the story.
Now, with formats, there are 20 or so
buckets that typically dominate on
social media. Most creators end up with
like two to three hero formats that they
alternate between and then sometimes
they experiment on the edges trying to
see if one of the new ones can beat out
their core three formats. When you're
starting out, people typically
experiment till they find their core
ones. Now, I've built a visual database
of the top 20 formats with a bunch of
examples of each one. You can see that
here. I'll link it below for free if you
want to download and access it. But
here's how I approach formats in this
system. The first way is to just look at
that list of 20 and just pick one that
you think looks interesting and take a
shot, right? So, not really using data,
just using intuition. The second path is
to let the data tell you what formats
are also working best for your niche.
And of course, the Sandcastle's data CSV
that also has a column with all the
formats tagged. So, you can just again
go to Claude and ask it to break out the
best performing formats for you. And so,
this is exactly what I'd write in
Claude. Give me a breakout of all the
videos by storytelling format. rank them
based on the highest outlier score and
then list within each bucket all of the
individual links and the names of those
formats. Now, typically this analysis
very quickly will reveal the top
performing formats in your niche. And if
you're unsure of which format to try,
you really don't care about creativity.
You just want the best performing one.
Pick the top one on this list. For
example, the rating ranking and tier
list format that we have bucketed. You
could do ratings, you could do rankings,
you could do tier list, you could do
brackets. There's all these different
flavors within that bucket. So, what I
like to do is take that datadriven
analysis that Claude did and it has all
the unique URLs and then I'll just go
and open a bunch of the top ones within
a bucket I'm interested in and I'll just
see how the people actually executed it
visually. Once I find a unique flavor
that I like and think I can replicate,
well, then I'll take that as the model.
But easily that uses data to guide me to
the top performing ones and then my eyes
to kind of lock in on the flavor that I
want. Also, if you like scrolling to
discover new formats, you can always
scroll on Instagram and Tik Tok and just
copy the link to a video. And you can
actually paste it in the videos tab in
Sandcastles by pressing add video URL.
When you do that, it'll import that
one-off video in. And then when you
export your CSV, that will be included
in this analysis. Like I said, I won't
move forward to the next step until I
have my topic and format locked in based
on the Sand Castle's data because this
makes sure that I'm rowing in the right
direction. By doing it this way, I've
now saved myself a ton of time. I didn't
have to doom scroll and I've d-risked
because I'm using the topics and formats
that have already been proven to work.
Now, obviously, if your strategy or
niche requires more realtime stuff,
you're reacting to the news, so you need
like the timeliest stuff, then just
change the post date in Sandcastles from
3 months down to like 2, 3, or 7 days.
This will give you more real time.
There'll be less videos in there, but
these are like the newest bangers that
are coming out. The truth is, most
niches are evergreen. You could take a
video from four months ago and just
remix it to be relevant today, and it
will still crush. So, most people don't
need to do that, but if you're doing
this news reaction stuff, then yeah,
change the post date. By the way,
depending on when you're watching this,
on the Sand Castle side, we have
something brand new coming out that's
not in this video that will make what I
just walked through like a hundred times
easier. So, stay on the lookout for that
if you like this AIdriven workflow.
Essentially, if you're using sand
castles to make content, you're going to
be able to outrun anyone in your niche
that isn't. We're just making it
automatic. All right, the third step in
my process is the substance. And this
really is the sauce layer. This is where
all the creativity lives. This is the
part where you don't really use the data
for. You kind of go authentic, original,
whatever word you want to describe to
encompass your uniqueness. It's in the
substance. The substance really boils
down to two things. The first is your
contrarian take or non-obvious
perspective on the topic. And the second
is the evidence you give to support that
contrarian take. Things like facts or
case studies or stories or metaphors or
examples, things like that. Now, here's
how I run the substance part of the
process. First, I look at the topic and
I make sure it's specific enough to
react to, right? So, if you're looking
at the topic category, the broadest
thing like hooks or storytelling or Nike
or Apple, that's way too broad. So, you
need the actual topic. That would be the
category. You want the subtopic or
topic. And if you use the prompt that I
gave you and you do the sand castle to
claim, you're just going to be given the
topic, so you'll be all good. But if you
do it some other way, just make sure
you're looking at the topic level unique
enough that you could actually react to
it. So, first I start with the
contrarian take or non-obvious takeaway.
And this really is what makes great
videos. This piece right here, the
contrarian take is basically something
you believe to be true about the topic
that most people do not. But then once
you reveal it, they could quickly get on
board to think that it's true as well.
So for example, let's just say the topic
category that surfaced for me was hooks.
And then the specific topic I was
working on was how to write better
hooks. That was like validated by the
data and that's what I'm working on. If
I'm trying to come up with a contrarian
take, I would then ask myself, what do I
believe about how to write better hooks
that I strongly think is true that most
people would be shocked to hear or not
believe today? So, I would write down
all the things that I know to be true
about how to write better hooks. And
that might include things like the first
sentence has to give context and have
zero fluff. So, like no delay. The first
sentence needs to be super punchy and
less than 12 words. The first sentence
needs to be written in fifth grade
language with really simple vocabulary.
But then maybe I think, wait a second,
actually the most valuable thing I could
tell them about writing a killer hook
actually has nothing to do with the
spoken hook. It's actually that the text
hook is 10 times more valuable and that
the text on screen is where your eyes go
first and then bingo. That epiphany
moment right there, that realization by
me is like actually the interesting part
is something over here that they weren't
thinking about. That's a contrarian
take. That's a non-obvious insight.
That's where the gold comes from in
content. So, the genius of being good at
content is really how easily you can
come up with these non-obvious
contrarian insights about whatever topic
you're making. And most of those come
really easy when you actually have legit
experience or expertise in an area.
That's why if you ever follow someone
and watch their videos, but the things
they say are always just replications
from someone else that you've already
heard, well, don't ever pay that person
for services because they don't actually
know what they're talking about, right?
They're not coming up with non-obvious
things, meaning they don't have
expertise outside the box in this area.
Now, once you figure out what the
contrarian take is in this substance
bucket, the rest of this process for
substance actually becomes a lot more
straightforward. The other part of the
substance step is the evidence. And when
I say evidence, what I mean is all the
other stuff you're going to say in the
video other than the contrarian take.
Now, this evidence, just like with a
lawyer, it's meant to support or prove
the contrarian take to be true. Because
once you say something that people don't
believe, you only have a limited amount
of time to convince them that they
should give you a chance and believe it.
So this evidence could be facts,
metaphors, stories, case studies,
examples, could even be opinions,
something to prove your take to be true.
So in the case of my hooks example where
I have this like non-obvious take around
the title text, I would then ask myself,
okay, what evidence could I show to
prove that my claim of title text
matters way more than spoken hook
actually is right? Well, one thing I
could show is proof. I could just show a
bunch of videos having title text with
no spoken hook with a bunch of views.
That could work. Another thing I could
do is show A versus B. one video
flopping and one crushing in the exact
same hook, but one has title text and
one doesn't. That could work. I could
also explain the psychology of why the
brain sees words faster than it hears.
That's more of like a theoretical
scientific explanation, but that could
work. Or I could do a combination of all
those things, right? So, I'm going
through this process of being like, what
evidence could I manufacture or have to
support my take? And that's the process
of putting together a winning video.
Now, the question is, where can you use
AI in this process to speed that flow
up? I'll say this, coming up with a
contrarian take using AI in like one
shot off one prompt. Coming up with it
is pretty tough. You could ask AI to
come up with contrarian takes on the
topic, but I find AI is good at
regurgitating what it's been trained on
and what it's heard. It's not great at
coming up with novel things outside the
box. However, once you do come up with a
contrarian take, you could use AI to be
like, "Hey, here's my topic. Here's my
format. Here's my contrarian take. What
evidence could make sense to use to
start supporting this take to be true?"
That it's good at. And so this is kind
of like the research on the take that
you might be able to do. Sometimes if
I'm feeling lazy and I don't want to
think for 30 minutes trying to come up
with the research, I'll just throw it
into Claude and be like, "Give me some
ideas for what I could use." That will
start spinning the wheels and then the
script will come out tighter. So if I'm
doing that, I would say something in
Claude like this. Hey, I'm making a
video about this topic. My contrarian
take is this. Can you help me think
through what the evidence or research
would need to be for this claim to make
sense? So in that case, I'm kind of
using Claude like a brainstorming
research partner, per se. Now, no matter
which way you do it, this substance
piece, the contrarian take and the
evidence supporting it, that really is
the foundational block for what great
content comes from. This is what I call
the last mile of great ideas. Now,
there's one more point I want to mention
on this substance piece, and that has to
do with the format you chose. If you
have a fairly restrictive format, that
can kind of dictate the flow of how the
evidence can be presented and what that
contrarian take could even be in the
first place. For example, if I'm making
a video about hooks, but I chose S tier
rank format, then I can't make the
contrarian take around the text hook
because I have to just rank hook types
in the S A B C DF visual. So, it
completely changes what I can use to fit
the format. So, in that case, my
contrarian take might be a certain type
of hook that everyone thinks is good,
but I rank bad or vice versa. But in
that case, the format helped put rails
on how I came up with the contrarian
take. So if you need help coming up with
these contrarian takes and you struggle
to do it, picking a more restrictive
format, putting guard rails on you can
actually be kind of helpful in the
development process. Constraints breed
creativity is like a common frame. So if
you add more constraints, you might be
able to be more creative. For example,
formats like the clone format that you
always see Ava doing, the A versus B
vers, or something like rating, ranking,
or tier list. These are more restrictive
formats that give you a set narrative
that you can play within. If you're like
me and you want to freestyle more
because you have like wild ideas, you
want to explain them. Well, then you
want a looser, more flexible format like
breakdown or case study or scenario. All
right. Now, at this point in the video,
we're halfway through the six-step
process. We've done topic, we've done
format, and we've done substance. And
those three things really combine
together to create the idea. When you
hear people talk about ideas is all that
matters, it's really a combo of those
three things. And this is where most of
the sauce is. When you build an AI
content system, what you're doing is
freeing up all your time so that you can
focus on what that non-obvious
contrarian take is and developing it.
That's what all the pros in content are
doing. But as you can see, I'm using AI
in every step of the way. I'm using AI
fully for topics. I'm using AI mostly
for formats almost always. And then I'm
coming up with the contrarian tech on my
own. And I'm using AI as a thought
partner for the evidence development.
All right, the fourth step in this flow
is the hook. Everybody talks about the
hook. Everybody cares about the hook.
Once you have the topic, the format, and
the substance, then it's time to move to
the hook. And we all know the hook is
made up of three things. The visual
hook, which is what's shown, the text
hook, which is the title text on screen,
and the spoken hook, which is what is
said and what the captions usually say.
Now, here's how I run my hook
development process. I do the same thing
every time. First, I start with the
spoken hook, and I go back to the data
that I pulled from Sand Castles. I go to
Claude and I say this. I want you to run
an analysis on all the hooks that we've
pulled from the top 100 videos. First, I
want you to bucket the videos by
storytelling format. Rank the
performance of the videos within each
format based on outlier score. Extract
out the hooks that were used for each
one and extract out the hook Mad Lib
format that's plug-andplay. I want you
to list out the original topic, the
video URL, the hook that was used, and
the Mad Lib hook format. So that when I
give you a new topic and I tell you what
storytelling format I'm using, I want
you to pull all the hooks from within
that bucket and generate all new hooks
using those Mad Lib hook formats. No
matter what topic I give you, depending
on how many hooks this nets me, maybe
I'll ask you to run this hook conversion
process again for another storytelling
format that is adjacent. I want you to
build this into a hookw writing skill
and let me know when you're ready for my
first topic. So by doing it this way,
what you're essentially doing is
bucketing all the videos by format.
you're getting all the hooks within that
bucket and ranking them. And then when
you pick a format, you can say just use
the other hooks that worked for that
format for mine. Essentially, it's a
data driven hook machine, but it's
matching up the hooks by format. If
you're not getting enough that way, you
can expand to other formats. And I like
matching the hooks by format. If you're
doing an S tier video, the best way to
find a winning hook is to look at all
other S tier video hook formats and be
like, which one crushed? And then use
that. Sometimes hooks don't transport
well across formats. Sometimes they do,
sometimes they don't. So that's why I
like keeping the format consistent at
first. Now, after I get the spoken hook,
the written hook down, locked in. I'll
then go watch the individual videos from
within that format category. That's why
I asked for the link. I'll open it and
I'll just watch every single one in a
new tab. And what I'm doing here is I'm
studying the visual hook execution and
the text hook. I can do this faster with
my eyes than I could from a visual AI
telling me like, oh, put the block up
there. I can just do it way faster with
my eyes. So, I like opening them up and
looking at it. Once I find one that
actually hooked me, then I will mimic
that visual execution. If you're doing
this and you see a text hook that you
really like that your eyes went to and
you got it right away, write that down.
That could be some version of the copy
that you write on your text hook. All
right, step five in the flow is the
script. So, at this point, we now have a
topic that is validated by data. We have
a format that's validated by data. We
have a non-obvious contrarian take that
we feel good about. We have evidence to
support that. And we have a hook written
in the style of our topic and format.
Now, I found that AI writing platforms,
none of them are great at writing
scripts out of the box. You'll never
find one without tuning it that's good
enough. So, this is what I do. I make my
own script profile based on my
transcripts, or you could do it off a
transcript of another creator that you
like. So, you're going to go back to
Sand Castles. This time you're going to
make sure either your profile or
whatever the profile of the creator you
want to train a voice model on. You want
to make sure they're in your watch list.
Go to the videos tab. Click the channel
filter. Click just them so it pulls up
only their videos. Again, sort by
outlier score, 2% for the minimum bound
of engagement, and go back like last 6
months. So, this is that person's best
performing videos. Now, what you want to
do is analyze like 10 to 20 of them.
Make sure to skip any ones where the
format is weird. It doesn't match what
you want. Like if they did a about me
video that's kind of like more
storytelling, narrative driven, and
that's not what you want, we'll skip
that one. Just get 10 to 20 videos that
are around the same style, the same
format, top performers, analyze all of
those. Now, you're going to export that
CSV with just those and you're going to
import that into Claude. And again, if
you already have winners in your own
voice, just do it with your own videos.
Don't copy some other creator if you
already have your own voice dialed. But
you don't have a voice dialed that you
want, go ahead and pick one other
creator that you want to mimic the tone
and rhythm and use them. I don't
recommend combining multiple creators
here because oftentimes, you know,
speaking patterns are like fingerprints.
I do it one way, they do it one way, she
does it one way. If you combine examples
from all three, it'll confuse the writer
and make it generic. So, you want to
pick one focused person and have 10 to
20 of the top performing transcripts
from that person. Export those out. Now,
you have the CSV. When I go back to
Claude, I open a new chat because this
is kind of like a new thread. Drop the
CSV in. And then this is what I prompt
for the scripting profile. I'm looking
to build a short form scripting profile
based on the transcripts that I've just
uploaded. First, I want you to take all
the transcripts and fix if there are any
small typos or weird things. Rewrite and
fix them so they're clean. Then, I want
you to take all those clean transcripts,
feed them in, and build a short form
script writing profile model based on
these. I want to be able to feed you a
topic, a format, a contrarian take, and
a hook. And I want you to be able to
write a script in the tone, rhythm, and
style of the script model you've just
made. I want you to save this as a
script writing skill. So, anytime I make
a new video, I can open this and let it
rip. Now, once you have this written,
it'll shock you how good this is. It'll
get you probably 90 to 95% of the way
there, especially if you already do the
work on the evidence. You already have
the hook. You have a lot of the bones
already there. You're not relying on it
to come up with new stuff. When most
people say AI writing is trash, what
they mean is AI coming up with certain
facts that are net new and writing it
together sounds kind of mid. But if you
actually guide it with a lot of the
datadriven research and you already have
a script model cloned based on the voice
and rhythm you like, it's going to get
you pretty close. From here, of course,
you may still need to go the last mile.
You may still need to tweak 5%. There
might be one or two sentences or one or
two things you want to tweak, but that's
about as close as you can get right now.
At this point, go ahead and take that
script and record. All right, the last
step in the flow, which is step six, is
the editing. At this point, every single
step has had a lot of AI driving it, but
we still preserve the creativity,
originality, which comes from the
contrarian take. Now, for those people
that say editing doesn't matter, there
are some formats that are lower frills
where editing is not really required. I
still think editing matters a lot from a
visual storytelling perspective. There's
so much emotion you can drive with the
right pacing and the right visuals, but
there's a wide spectrum in how you could
approach this. You really have four ways
to tackle editing. So, it's kind of
dealer's choice and how you want to do
it. The first way is to intentionally
pick a format that doesn't really
require a ton of editing. This would be
like yapping or the clone style or, you
know, just like more raw personal
storytelling without a ton of editing.
This would be the first pass. You can
bypass editing with this. Do this if you
don't have the time. It's going to be
harder to cut through with these. You
really need to dial in everything else
if you're going to go this way. The
second way would be to brute force the
editing yourself. You pick whatever
format you think is best based on the
data. And no matter what it takes, you
brute force it. This is what I did. You
could do it in Cap Cut. You could do it
in Reals. You could do it in Premiere
Pro. I taught myself how to do it until
I could outsource it. The third way
that's starting to emerge is people are
using claude code and a remotion skill
to actually automate some of the editing
with AI. I don't think this is very
premium yet. It's still like 2 out of
10, three out of 10 in terms of the
complexity, but this is starting to
work. If you're non-technical and you
don't want to spend all the time
learning this, I wouldn't put all the
eggs in this basket. However, this is
emerging. I'll continue to comment on it
as it gets better. The fourth way to
tackle editing is to hire an editor and
outsource it. The reason I don't talk
about editing in detail on this channel
the way I do about all the other stuff
is because if you're a business owner or
you're trying to build an actual revenue
engine from content, you should not be
editing. You cannot be editing. It's too
low leverage of a task for you as the
creator to be doing it. So, I recommend
outsourcing this. I've got a bunch of
editors on every single one of my teams.
If you want to work with the same people
I work with for these YouTube videos,
for all my shorts on tech, all my shorts
on marketing, I've got a link below. You
can fill that out and I will connect
you. All right, so that is it really.
That's the full endto-end sauce in terms
of one rep for the workflow. Its topic,
its format, its substance, its hooks,
scripts, and edits. We talked about in
every single one of those pieces, you
can use AI to automate a lot of it other
than the edit, but you could use
Remotion if you wanted to do that as
well. Now, my kind of macro meta
perspective is a thing called AI enabled
creativity. This is kind of what I'm
going all in on. What I think AI is
great for is taking away all the boring
stuff so that you can spend all your
time creating. It's not that AI is going
to remove human creativity. It's that it
frees up human creativity. That's how
I'm looking at it. So, for me, me coming
up with these crazy metaphors and wild
concepts like dopamine ladders or all
the stuff I do in the videos, that takes
time to cook that up. I don't have as
much time when I have to do all this
4-hour editing or 3-hour research
sprints. But if I can use AI to
outsource all of that, I can spend all
my time cooking up the cool stuff. And
that's what I think the power really is
when you build one of these systems.
Now, the question you would have from
here, this last piece I want to cover is
what I call my 10x batch system. Cuz
really what you're wondering is, okay,
that was one rep, but how do I actually
like run the system over and over? How
do I know what to make over time? Do I
do this every time? How do I sequence
it? Let me just explain how I approach
this flow. You're going to run that
whole loop that I just said once and
that's going to produce 10 videos,
right? So, the topic, format, research,
that one pull should inform 10 videos.
You're going to go substance all the way
down. Substance all the way down. All
the way down. All the way down 10 times.
So that first part you're going to run
once and then you're going to have that
substance hook, script, editing flow 10
times. That's one batch of 10 videos.
You're going to post each one of those
videos every day back to back for 10
days. Now, once you post the 10, I want
you to look backwards at the analytics
and I want you to look at three
different metrics. These the only three
metrics that matter for content. Number
one, and I think the most important is
conversions per video or conversions per
view. So, if you have a lead magnet or a
low ticket product and you're actually
able to track via many chat the
conversions off the video, this is the
absolute best metric to measure and
you're going to look at how many
conversions did I drive per video. If
you can't track that or you don't have a
backend built out, the next best thing
would be to look at followers per video
or followers per view. How many
followers did this video drive? Now,
followers themselves don't matter in
terms of you getting reach, but a follow
from a human psychologically is a proxy
for an endorsement that is bigger than a
view. If someone presses follow, they're
like, "Wow, I really like this guy's
stuff. I really like this girl's
content." That is higher weighted than
them just watching something that was
given to them automatically. So, if you
can't look at conversions, you want to
look at followers gained per video and
use that to guide. The worst metric of
the three, but still way better than
everything else, is just total views.
You're going to look at how many views
you got relative to the field. So, what
I want you to do is after you post a
batch of 10, I want you to look
backwards and be like, did any of the 10
get at least a 5x above the average for
any of those three metrics. Did any of
them drive 5x more conversions, 5x more
followers, or 5x more views than the
average of the 10. Now, here's how
you're going to treat this. If none of
them got above a 5x, they were all at
the average, and ideally the average is
probably low, that means you're going to
rerun this process from scratch the next
batch, right? And typically when this
doesn't happen, there's usually like an
obvious thing that's wrong with your
videos or several obvious things. I
actually put a program together where if
you need help, I just literally review
your videos myself and I say like, "Fix
that. Fix that. Ooh, that's why that's
not working. Your hook's not working."
Every single call twice a week. I just
go through everyone's videos as a group,
one-on-one videos, but so everyone can
see them. And I'm just like, "That's not
working. That's not working. Oh, you
messed that up. You messed that up."
It's really helpful. So if you want
that, I've linked it below. We've just
opened a few spots. You don't have to
have it forever, but it's really helpful
for you to scale. If you get feedback
from me, so that's if nothing is above a
5x. Now, if you get one or more that's
above a 5x, but not above a 10x. It's
kind of in this 5 to 10x range, that
means you've got a winner, and you're
going to take that topic and format, and
you're going to tweak it slightly when
your next batch, three of the 10 in the
next batch should follow that topic and
format. So, for me, in the example,
hooks was the category, how to write
better hooks was a topic, and the format
was a breakdown. If I get a 5x, I'm
going to be like, "Okay, how to write
better hooks. Is there another
contrarian take I could share? Could I
tweak it somehow? Maybe try a different
format?" Because you have data telling
you that that video outperformed. Now,
if you have a 10x or more, you're going
to take the exact same topic, the exact
same format, and you're going to run it
again. That is like liquid gold. So,
when you have a winner, five or 10x,
you're going to run it three of your
next 10. You're not going to run all 10
like that cuz it's going to get way too
repetitive for you and the viewer. But
three of your next 10 are going to be
like that. If you have three winners,
well, that takes care of your next 10.
This is called the 10x batch process.
You run these batches of 10, you look
backwards, you take a winner, and you
carry it forward. What you're really
looking to do is to have three different
combinations of winners that just crush
10x. That will inform your entire batch
process. So, every time you make one of
10, they just crush. All you have to do
is continue running iterative loops of
10, getting better from video to video,
and taking forward the ones that worked,
and you'll be good. Like I said, if you
want help from me reviewing, this is
really what I do. Like I get on the call
and I just review everyone's videos
one-on-one. They put their videos in the
chat and I just say, "Cool, let me watch
this." We all watch it together and I
just give feedback live. If you want me
to cook on your videos and just solve
this for you, I've got a link below. Few
spots open. All right, guys. That is all
I've got for this video. This was a long
one. You can tell in my voice I'm I'm
cooked. To be honest, like this level of
detail should not be given away for
free, but I really do want to see all
you guys win. Like I said in previous
videos, my goal is I want a million
people to make a million dollars from
content. That's a trillion dollars in
market value. in order to get you guys
there, I need to give you every single
thing I can. So, that's why I'm making
these videos one of one for you. If
you're watching this and you're like,
"Man, that was amazing. I can't believe
he gives this for free. What can I do to
help?" If you're thinking that, this is
what would really help me. Subscribe to
the channel if you haven't already
subscribed. If you have subscribed,
especially like the video and leave a
comment. And the comment I just want to
be the chef emoji with the mustache.
That's like my bat signal cuz I'm
cooking, right? I'm cooking on these
videos. Just drop the chef emoji cold.
No other context but that. If you do
that, you're a real one. I want to be
able to look back on the videos and just
see chef, chef, chef, chef, chef, chef,
chef. Like, everyone's just chefing. If
you do that, that means you got all the
way through and you actually locked in
this information. So, that's all I ask
from you guys. I got a ton of stuff for
free below. I mentioned several free
things throughout the video. You can
just grab those, the prompts, the visual
database. You can use that. Like I said,
I really want to see you guys win. So,
hopefully you enjoyed that video. That's
all I've got on this one and we will see
you guys on the next one. Peace.